propay.com 2017-01-19

# Privacy Policy

## Last Revised: May 22, 2015.  The most current version of this Privacy Policy may be viewed at any time on the ProPay website.

## Summary

This Privacy Policy covers the websites www.propay.com and [www.propaypayments.com](http://www.propaypayments.com/), both owned and operated by ProPay, Inc. “ProPay”. ProPay works hard to earn and keep your trust and confidence. This Privacy Policy is posted at our web site to allow users easy and quick access to ProPay's policy regarding personal information. This notice explains how we collect and safeguard information about you and the choices you have about our use and disclosure of that information.

**  THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLIES ONLY TO THOSE PEOPLE LIVING WITHIN THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA  
**

## Required Information

We obtain information about you from a variety of sources. You provide information about yourself, for example, by completing the ProPay Account sign-up form. This form asks for your first and last name, e-mail address, mailing address, day and evening telephone number, Social Security number, date of birth and the creation of your unique password. Information about you may also be obtained from credit-reporting agencies, ProPay Affiliates, other third-party commercial vendors to financial services firms, and/or your use of ProPay's services. We call this information, "Merchant Account Information." Merchant Account Information is used to identify you, prevent possible fraud, and in connection to delivering ProPay Account services to you.

Unique identifier information is used to qualify for, and set up, a ProPay Account. Refusal to fully complete the sign-up form by entering accurate information will result in ProPay not being able to provide services to you. Credit card and checking account information is required to use specific services of ProPay and is used only to process those transactions you have initiated. Also, personal information from third parties may be collected by ProPay on behalf of merchants from the third parties with whom the merchant engages in business as a result of their connection with ProPay.  This third party personal information may include, but is not limited to, contact information of the third party, such as name, address, and social security number, as well as credit card information.  In the event this information is requested of the third party and collected by ProPay, ProPay shall only use this information pursuant to the purposes delineated and contemplated by this Privacy Policy as further set forth herein.

## Disclosure of Information

We use Merchant Account Information in connection with delivering payment services to you. In order to conduct financial payment-related transactions and/or to effectively deliver payment services securely to you, while minimizing the risks of financial loss, it is often necessary to communicate such Merchant Account Information to or with financial institutions such as Visa®, MasterCard®, Discover® Card Services, banking institutions involved in supporting, clearing or settling payment-related transactions, our corporate Affiliates and/or other companies we work with.

ProPay takes numerous commercially reasonable measures to protect the personal information that you share. In the event your Merchant Account becomes delinquent, you authorize ProPay to disclose and communicate all your Merchant Account Information to third parties for the purpose of collection of any delinquent amount. If you initiate a transaction that requires credit card and checking account information, ProPay uses that information only to process your payment request and will not use it for marketing purposes. ProPay may also disclose information as required by law to governmental regulatory agencies. For example, we may disclose Merchant Account Information in response to lawful subpoenas or similar legal process, to credit-reporting agencies, and when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, to help prevent fraud or to respond to a government request. Any third party, including by way of example and not limitation, service providers or agents, or processors with whom ProPay shares your personal information shall only be permitted to use this personal information for the purposes set forth above and which are contemplated by this Privacy Policy.  The types of third parties with whom ProPay shares your personal information shall be limited to those delineated in the foregoing, and your personal information shall not be shared with third parties which fall outside the scope of this Privacy Policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

If ProPay is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

## Security

We take commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural steps to help safeguard your Merchant Account Information. Our web site takes precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the web site, we take reasonable commercial measures to protect your information both online and off-line.

When the registration form or a transaction form asks you to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number, checking account information, and/or your Social Security number), that information is electronically encrypted and is protected using secure socket layer technology (SSL). While on a secure page, such as the registration form or transaction forms, the lock icon on the bottom of web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer, becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just 'surfing'.

While we follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it, we also take additional reasonable commercial measures to protect your information offline. All your information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (such as ProPay's database administrators, security department employees, and customer service representatives) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Furthermore, all employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Periodically, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance of privacy and what they can do to ensure our customers' information is protected. The servers that store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about the security at ProPay's web site, please contact us at ProPay Customer Service.

Back to top

## Cookies and other Tracking technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by ProPay and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics and our service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to remember user settings and for user authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data.

We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality.

Third parties provide certain features on our site, e.g., tracking visitors to our websites or displaying advertising based upon your Web browsing activity using LSOs such as Flash to collect and store information. To manage Flash LSOs please click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>

## Advertising

Third parties display advertising on our Web sites and manage our advertising on other sites. These third parties may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

## Links

ProPay's web site may contain links to other web sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other web sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave the ProPay web site and to read the privacy policy of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by this web site.

## E-mail Links

ProPay uses e-mail links located on the "contact us" page to allow you to contact us directly with any questions or comments. We read every message sent in and try to reply promptly to everyone. This information is used to respond directly to your questions or comments. We may also file your comments to improve the web site and program or may review and discard the information.

## Blog

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [email].  In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

## Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements.  With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name.  If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [marketing@propay.com](mailto:marketing@propay.com).

## Social Media Features

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Twitter and Facebook buttons. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Following ProPay on Twitter or Liking the ProPay Facebook page enables us to collect information such as age demographics, location, interests, email address and other information you make available directly or indirectly via your account settings in Twitter and Facebook. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Referral Program

When available, if you elect to use the ProPay referral service for informing a friend about ProPay, we will ask you for the friend's name and e-mail address. We will automatically send the friend a one-time e-mail inviting them to visit the web site and register for the service. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail.

## Newsletter, Promotions and Correspondence

ProPay sends all new members a welcoming e-mail. By registering with ProPay, you also agree to receive e-mail notifications and confirmations that are not optional (such as transaction details, changes made to your profile, etc.) when using our payment systems. Established members will receive information on special promotions and a newsletter, including product and service updates. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please refer to the "Opting Out" section below.

We may occasionally present a special promotion. To qualify for entry, we may ask you to provide personal information. If we plan to share that information with any sponsor(s), we will inform you of that intent in the specific newsletter or promotion.

## Opting Out

You are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of receiving further information from ProPay about special promotions or product updates. The registration form has an 'opt-out' mechanism so you can choose whether you want marketing material or product updates. If you no longer wish to receive service updates or promotional materials from ProPay, you may opt-out of receiving these communications by editing your ProPay Account profile after you have logged into your account. Also, you have the option to opt-out from taking receipt of notifications and promotional information sent to you via email by ProPay.  You may elect to do so, and thereby unsubscribe from email correspondence, by simply following the unsubscribe instructions which will be provided in each email correspondence sent to you by ProPay or you can contact us at [customerservice@propay.com](mailto:customerservice@propay.com).

## Surveys

From time-to-time we may request information from you via surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information and demographic information. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of our service and/or this web site.

## Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy to reflect the changes to our information practices, or if we make any material changes, we will notify you via your current e-mail address on file with ProPay or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective so you are always aware of what information is collected, how it is used, and under which circumstances, if any, information is disclosed. If at any time we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from what is stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you by way of an e-mail. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Back to top

## Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## For Vermont Account Holders Only

If your ProPay Merchant Account has a Vermont billing address, we will automatically treat your account as if you had opted out as set forth in this notice. We may share your name and contact information, and information about our transactions or experiences with you, with credit reporting agencies.

## How to Access and Update Your Personal Information

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove on our site or deactivate it by clicking the Edit My Profile link after you log on to your ProPay Account or by contacting us at ProPay Customer Service or at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

## Contact Us

ProPay, Inc.

3400 N Ashton Blvd.

Suite 200

Lehi, UT 84043

Please include your old and new contact information so that ProPay can make the appropriate corrections.

## TRUSTe Information

ProPay, Inc. has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal.  The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software, mobile application and through other services.  The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the Web sites www.propay.com and www.propayments.com.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.

Back to top
